Mystery loves company.
Scoob! is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Tony Cervone.
In Scooby-Doo’s greatest adventure yet, see the never-before told story of how lifelong friends Scooby and Shaggy first met
and how they joined forces with young detectives Fred, Velma, and Daphne to form the famous Mystery Inc.
Now, with hundreds of cases solved, Scooby and the gang face their biggest, toughest
mystery ever: an evil plot to unleash the ghost dog Cerberus upon the world.
As they race to stop this global “dogpocalypse,” the gang discovers that Scooby has a
secret legacy and an epic destiny greater than anyone ever imagined.
Shaggy Rogers (voice), played by Will Forte.
Scooby-Doo / Pterodactyl (voice), played by Frank Welker.
Blue Falcon (voice), played by Mark Wahlberg.
Dick Dastardly (voice), played by Jason Isaacs.
Dynomutt, Dog Wonder (voice), played by Ken Jeong.
Daphne Blake (voice), played by Amanda Seyfried.
is a 2020 American animated mystery comedy film produced by Warner
Animation Group, and distributed by Warner Bros.
It is a reboot of the theatrical Scooby-Doo film series and the third theatrical film based on the
characters, following Scooby-Doo (2002) and Scooby-Doo 2: Monsters Unleashed (2004).
The film is directed by Tony Cervone (in his feature directorial debut) from a screenplay by Adam Sztykiel, Jack
Donaldson, Derek Elliott, and Matt Lieberman, and a story by Lieberman, Eyal Podell, and Jonathon E.
It stars the voices of Frank Welker, Will Forte, Gina
Rodriguez, Zac Efron, and Amanda Seyfried.
The film also features the voices of Mark Wahlberg (in his voice role debut), Jason Isaacs, Kiersey
Clemons, Ken Jeong, and Tracy Morgan as other animated Hanna-Barbera characters.
Set in a Hanna-Barbera animated shared universe, the film follows Mystery Incorporated working with the Blue Falcon to solve their most
challenging mystery behind their mascot's secret legacy and purpose, which connects with Dick Dastardly's evil plan to unleash Cerberus.
Plans for a new Scooby-Doo theatrical film began in June 2014, when Warner Bros.
announced that they would reboot the Scooby-Doo
film series with an animated film.
Cervone was hired to direct the film in August 2015, with Dax Shepard being brought to co-direct
it in September 2016, until he was no longer part of the project by October 2018.
Warner Bros.
then hired Chris Columbus, whose "affection for the character" made him an executive producer on the final
film, while the studio “understands how much of its history is rooted in these iconic characters”.
was originally set for a worldwide theatrical release on May 15, 2020.
In response to the COVID-19 pandemic causing the closure
of theaters across the globe, Warner Bros.
made the film available to own digitally in the United States on the
same date it was planned to be released in theaters.
It received a theatrical release in select countries beginning in July 2020 and a
secondary theatrical release in the United States beginning on May 21, 2021.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who criticized its meme references.
The film grossed $28.5 million against a budget of $90 million, but it topped digital rental charts in its
first three weekends of release, becoming the third-most watched title on PVOD in 2020.
A prequel, Scoob!
Holiday Haunt, was originally set for release through HBO Max; it was cancelled in August
2022, although production on the film was completed after the cancellation.
The film explores themes of friendship,
superhero, villain, heroism, talking dog.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.